孤儿怨
首杀
翻译：大旺财
爱沙尼亚 2007年
我是安娜·特罗耶夫，艺术治疗导师
I'm Anna Troyev, the art therapy instructor.
手举起来
Arms up.
我希望以后不必每天都这样
I trust we won't go through this every day.
安娜
Anna?
欢迎
Welcome.
准备好了吗？   你的第一天
Are you ready for your first day?
我想是的
I think so.
请.
Please.
你住得远吗?
Do you live far?
有点，但这不要紧
Somewhat, but it's worth it.
我一直想用艺术来帮助人们
I've always wanted to use art to help people.
太棒了
Wonderful.
请
Please.
这边
This way.
这是我们的安全程序规则
Those are our security procedures.
好好看看吧
Learn them backwards and forwards.
我们的病人大多数都很温顺，但其他的
Most of our patients are quite docile, but others..
医生，是莉娜
Doctor, it's Leena.
她不在房间里，没人能找到她
She's not in her room, nobody can find her.
[爱沙尼亚语]
[speaking in Estonian]
上锁
Lock it.
全部锁上
Full on lock out!
莉娜是谁
Who is Leena?
我们最危险的病人
Our most dangerous patient.
事实上，她就是你这个职位空缺出来的原因
In fact, she's the reason for the opening you're filling.
你的前任低估了她还忽略了协议
Your predecessor underestimated her and ignored protocol.
导致结果并不好
It did not end well.
听我说
Listen to me.
不要离开这个房间
Do not leave this room.
别担心，你在这里很安全
Don't worry, you'll be safe here
找到她后我会回来的
and I'll come back after we found her.
拜托   拜托
Please, please.
你好
Hello there.
你爸爸妈妈在这里工作吗
Does your mom or dad work here?
我能看看吗？
Could I see?
那是我吗
Is that me?
画得真好
That's very good.
我是安娜
I'm Anna.
你叫什么名字
What's your name?
莉娜
Leena.
你还没有回答我刚才的问题
You didn't a-answer me before.
你父母在这里工作吗？
Do your parents work here?
你为什么会这么想？
Why would you think that?
- 因为你…                - 我什么？
- Because you're..   - I'm what?
莉娜
Leena..
[爱沙尼亚语]
[speaking in Estonian]
放下它
Put it down.
莉娜，把它放下  快点
Leena, put it down now.
你刚才没告诉我她是个孩子
You didn't tell me she was a child.
因为她不是
It's because she's not.
莉娜患有腺体疾病
Leena suffers from a gland disorder.
这导致了比例均衡的侏儒症
Which causes proportional dwarfism,
在她十岁左右身体基本上停止了生长
essentially halting her growth around age ten.
别搞错了，莉娜可能看起来像个孩子
Make no mistake, Leena may look like a child,
但她是个成年女人
but she is a grown woman.
确切地说31岁了
31 to be exact.
当莉娜第一次来的时候，她拼命地挣脱束缚
When Leena first arrived, she struggled so hard against
可是这束缚使得她流血不止
her restraints that she would bleed severely.
这对我们所有人来说都是一个教训，让我们知道
It was a lesson for all of us on the depths of her
她渴望自由的意志有多么强烈
will to be free.
莉娜早年的大部分时间都是为了生存
Much of Leena's early life was spent doing whatever she
而竭尽所能
could to survive.
但她从来没有长大,    至少在外表上没有
But she never grew older, at least not on the outside.
想象一下，在你的一生中
Imagine, going through your whole life
整个世界都把你当成一个孩子
with the world only seeing a child.
你不能这样看她，这很重要
It is very important that you do not see her in that way.
莉娜带来的痛苦和她遭受到的痛苦一样多
Leena uses her affliction as much as she suffers from it.
她是个杰出的骗子
She's an exceptional con artist.
两年前，莉娜伪装成离家出走的儿童
Two years ago, Leena wormed her way into this family
混进了这个家庭
by posing as a runaway.
这家人收留了她，给她吃的，给她穿的
This family took her in, they fed her, they clothed her.
通常情况下，莉娜只会偷点需要的东西 然后
Normally, Leena would simply steal whatever she could and
消失，但这次她…
disappear, but this time she...
嗯   我这么说吧，她现在住在这里
Well, let me put it this way, she lives here now.
依悌
Idti.
Idti!
她干的
She does that.
我们还有多久，爸爸
How much longer we got, daddy?
你还有几分钟，亲爱的
You have a few minutes, darling.
你记住我了吗，小莎拉?
You learning me by heart little Sara?
不，爸爸，我把你记在心里了
No, daddy, I know you by heart.
你就在我心里
You're inside my heart.
我们会很勇敢的，不是吗?
We're going to be brave, aren't we?
是的,爸爸
Yes, daddy.
但这将是我们最艰难的一场战斗
But this is gonna be our hardest battle.
你好，德米特里
Hello, Dmitri.
你很准时
You're on time.
非常好
It's perfect.
我自己系不上
I can't tie these myself.
我想为你做点好事
I want to do something nice for you.
你可以进来
You can come in.
我现在可以做到了
I can do it now.
我随时都能看到，我爸爸正回到我身边
Any moment I may see, my daddy coming back to me.
我不
I don't.
我爸爸要走了
My daddy has to go away.
[爱沙尼亚语]
[speaking Estonian]
依悌
Idti.
你想要点糖果吗?
Do you want some candy?
依悌
Idti!
她切断了信号
She cut the feed.
我很抱歉，安娜
I'm so sorry, Anna.
希望警察能在其他人受伤之前找到她
Hopefully, the police will find her before anyone else is hurt.
我想这不是我们想要的开始
Not quite the start we'd hoped for, I'm sure.
这份工作不适合我
This job isn't for me.
失踪儿童    美国    9-12岁
埃丝特-奥尔布赖特
失踪时间：2003年5月2日
哦  安娜
Oh, Anna.
我通常只杀一个人
It usually takes only one.
[爱沙尼亚语]                      谁在那里
[Speaking Estonian]           Who's there?
别怕，我是警察
Don't be afraid, I'm police.
嗯…你的父母在哪里?
Uh...Where are your parents?
我的父母在美国
My parents are in America.
亲爱的，你叫什么名字?
Sweetheart, what is your name?
我叫埃丝特
My name is Esther.
达里安镇，康涅狄格州
♪ Coming with me ♪
♪ Through the aging The fearing, the strife ♪
♪ It's the smiling On the package ♪
♪ It's the faces in the sand ♪
♪ It's the thought That moves you upwards ♪
♪ Embracing me with two hands ♪
♪ Right will take you places Yeah, maybe to the beach ♪
♪ When your friends They do come crying ♪
♪ Tell 'em Now your pleasure's set ♪
♪ Upon slow release ♪
♪ Hey, wait ♪
♪ Sensitive to fate, not... ♪
♪ The long way back ♪
♪ Sandy, why can't we Look the other way? ♪
-  你太棒了       - 谢谢 ,  伙计
- You killed it.  - Thanks, man.
为你骄傲，亲爱的
Proud of you, sweetheart.
耶  干得好，兄弟
Yeah, great job, pal.
谢谢 ,  伙计们
Thanks, guys.
你觉得你会待多久
How long do you think you'll be?
其实今晚   有很多人   要聚在一起
Actually a bunch of people are getting together tonight.
嗯,  恭喜
Well, congrats.
我们回家见
I'll see you guys back at the house.
我是说，这本该是家庭之夜
I mean, this was supposed to be family night.
怎么，他不该和朋友一起玩吗?
What, is he not supposed to have fun with friends?
哦  天啊，他就是玩得开心
Oh God, all he does is have fun.
不
No.
加纳拼命工作
Gunnar works his tail off.
除了学习，就是击剑
When he's not studying, he's fencing.
他过着自己的生活
He's living his life.
别这么做，别这么想
Don't do that, don't go into your head.
我需要你在场
I need you to be present.
加纳需要你
Gunnar needs you.
哦  抱歉，那场比赛我没去吗?
Oh, sorry, was I not at that match?
埃斯特不会回来了，艾伦
Esther's not coming back, Allen.
我也想她
I miss her too.
真的
I do.
每一天的每一刻
Every moment of every day.
他在这里做什么?
What's he doing here?
莫斯科市    俄罗斯
从我们从埃丝特那得到的信息来看
From the little we've gotten from Esther,
我们认为有个女人绑架了她，把她带到俄罗斯
we believe a woman abducted her, brought her to
冒充自己的孩子   直到埃斯特
Russia and passed her off as her own child until Esther
成功逃脱
managed to escape.
我们现在还没有多少细节
We haven't gotten many specifics yet.
也许等她觉得安全了，她就能告诉我们更多
Perhaps when she's feeling safer, she can shed some more
关于她的经历
light on what she's been through.
我们有一位儿童治疗师，她将与我们合作
We have a child therapist that she'll be working with.
好
Good.
但她现在需要的是她的家人
But what she needs right now is her family.
为新变化做好准备吧
Be prepared for changes.
四年对一个孩子的成长来说    是很长的一段时间
Four years is a long time in the development of a child.
埃丝特
Esther?
亲爱的, 是我,   是妈咪
Sweetheart, it's me, it's mommy.
我能，我能见你吗
Can I, can I see you?
亲爱的
Sweetie.
是妈咪
It's mommy.
我以为再也见不到你了
I thought I'd never see you again.
现在一切都很好
Everything is right now.
你已经很久没见到我们了
It's been so long since you've seen any of us.
看看我能不能…  哦,那是爹地
See if I can.. Oh, there's daddy.
这是我们的慈善活动之一
This was one of our charity events.
那天晚上他看起来很帅，不是吗?
He looks so handsome that night, didn't he?
还需要我帮你拿点什么吗?
Can I grab you anything else?
- 不，谢谢         - 好的
- No, thanks.    - Okay.
哦, 说到小恶魔,  你的哥哥可能
Oh, speak of the devil, your brother is probably a foot
比你还高一个头
taller than you'd remember.
哦   那是  嬷嬷
Oh, there's Mup-Mup.
她对我们太好了
She's been so good to us.
哦 我等不及想见她了
Oh, I can't wait to see her.
不  亲爱的
No, sweetie.
她去世了
She passed.
记得吗
Remember?
现在只有我们四个人了
It's just the four of us now.
我要上洗手间
I have to use the restroom.
啊，洗手间在那边吗?
Ah, is the restroom over there?
不，就在那边
No, it's just right back over there.
在后面？
Over in the back?
- 谢谢你的帮助                   - 不客气
- Thank you for your help.  - You're welcome.
我等不及要见你了
I can't wait to see you.
太愚蠢了
So stupid.
哦   爹地和加纳就在楼下
Oh, daddy and Gunnar are just downstairs.
你觉得父亲会认出我吗?
Do you think father will recognize me?
如果你一直叫他父亲，也许就不会了
Maybe not if you keep calling him father.
爸爸
Dad.
是的  这样好多了
Yeah. That's better.
来，让我看看你
Here, let me look at you.
天啊，你看起来   像个小淑女
Oh, my God, you look, like a little lady.
你长大了很多
You've grown up so much.
把这个摘掉
Take this off.
这样好多了   不那么严肃了
That's better. It's less austere.
这是
This is..
对不起
Sorry.
不，对 对不起，我…，来吧，我们走
No, I-I'm sorry, I.. Come on, let's go.
我想，我很紧张
I think, I'm nervous.
对，迈出了一大步
Right, big step.
爹地
Daddy.
真抱歉，我不敢相信真的是你
I'm so sorry, I can't believe it's really you.
我一直都知道
I always knew.
你好  加纳
Hello, Gunnar.
嘿
Hey.
我觉得我们可以做得比"嘿"好一点
I think we can do a little better than "hey,"
你说是不是
don't you think?
来吧
Come on.
我很高兴你回来了
Glad you're back.
我也是
Me too.
我们回家怎么样
How about we go home?
- 好的  - 让我们回家吧
- Yes!  - Let's go home.
欢迎回家 埃丝特
Welcome home, Esther.
我们让它保持着原样
We left it just as it was.
我们一直都知道你会回来的
We always knew you'd come back home.
我的意思是，你可能已经长大了很多
I mean you probably outgrown so much but we have a lot of
但我们有很多圣诞节和生日要弥补   所以只要
Christmases and birthdays to make up for, so just let us
告诉我们你喜欢什么  然后 你都能得到
know what you're into, and you might get it.
我喜欢绘画
I like painting.
你喜欢画画吗?
You like to paint?
你以前对绘画从不感兴趣
You were never interested in painting before.
好吧 也许你们俩可以在工作室待一段时间
Well, maybe you two can spend some time in your studio.
没有什么能让我更开心了
Nothing would make me happier.
嗯, 明天的计划是,  你先去找西格医生谈谈
So um, the plan is, tomorrow you're gonna talk to Dr. Segar.
你还记得她吗?
Do you remember her?
她  她养了一只叫雪梨的鹦鹉?
She, she had the parrot named Sydney?
好吧，如果你需要什么…
Well, if you need anything..
我们就在走廊尽头 好吗?
We're be right down the hall. Alright?
♪ And let your poor heart Break a little ♪
♪ That's the story of ♪
♪ That's the glory of love ♪
♪ You gotta laugh a little ♪
♪ Cry a little ♪
♪ Before the clouds Roll by a little ♪
♪ That's the story of That's the glory of love ♪
好的，你可以进去了
Okay, you can go in.
西格医生马上就来
Dr. Segar will be right with you.
我过几分钟就要见她了
I'm seeing her in few minutes.
我觉得你现在介入还为时过早，警官
I think it's too soon for you to get involved, detective.
我想先和她单独谈谈
I'd like to talk to her alone first.
听着，我得走了
Look, I have to go.
你不知道我见到你有多高兴，埃丝特
You have no idea how happy I am to see you, Esther.
欢迎回家
Welcome home.
现在，你已经不是我曾经认识的那个小女孩了
Well now, you are certainly not the little girl I once knew.
你现在是一个年轻的女士了
You're a young lady now.
你还记得我们刚开始治疗的时候
Do you remember what I told you
我是怎么跟你说的吗?
when we first began our sessions?
我告诉过你  如果我问的任何问题
I told you if I ask any questions that make you
让你不舒服   我们就停止
uncomfortable, we'll stop.
我希望我的父母能像你一样
I wish my parents were like you.
怎么了
How so?
他们一直问我发生了什么
They keep asking what happened to me,
但我还没准备好告诉他们
but I'm not ready to tell them about it.
这完全没问题
And that's perfectly fine.
我希望你能跟我谈谈
I am hoping you'll talk to me about it,
但前提是你准备好了，好吗?
but only when you're ready, okay?
话虽如此，你还有什么想告诉我的吗
Having said that, is there anything you want to tell me
关于你的离开的时间
about your time, away..
你想玩吗，雪梨?
You want to play, Sydney?
我觉得雪梨想和我一起玩
I think Sydney wants to play with me.
你好  我记得你
Hello. I remember you.
你还记得我吗?
Do you remember me?
到你了
Your turn.
埃丝特，你可以在外面等等吗，我要
Esther, you can wait out here, I'm just gonna need to
和你妈妈说几句话
talk to your mom for a moment.
你好
Hello.
嗨
Hi.
我喜欢你的耳环
I like your earrings.
哦，谢谢你，亲爱的
Oh, thank you, honey.
你在写什么?
What are you writing?
哦  我很抱歉
Oh! I'm sorry.
我真的很抱歉
I'm so sorry.
没 没关系
It's-it's okay.
对不起
I'm sorry.
我去把这里清理一下
I'm just gonna get this cleaned up.
她还和你记忆中的一样吗?
Does she seem the same as you remember?
不一样？
Different?
她当然不一样了
Well, of course she's different.
她现在有口音了
She has an accent now.
考虑到她去过的地方，这很不寻常吗?
Is that unusual, considering where she's been?
不一定，她在那里待了很长时间
Not necessarily, she was there a long time
那时她的语言能力还在发展
when her speech was still developing.
但我要告诉你，她的智力和情感状况
But I will tell you, she's in far better shape
比我想象的要好得多.
intellectually and emotionally than I would expect.
太好了  是吧？
That's good, right?
我也注意到了一些矛盾之处
I did also notice some inconsistencies.
比如，她说那是雪梨
For example, she said that was Sydney.
雪梨是一只金刚鹦鹉，亮橙色，比这只大四倍
Sydney was a macaw, bright orange and four times the size.
然而，今天，她称呼这只鸟为雪梨
Yet, today, she addressed this bird as Sydney
自信满满的
with complete confidence.
你是什么意思?
What are you getting at?
对我来说，这就像是一场表演
To me, it felt like a performance.
他打了我，扯破了我的衣服
He hit me and ripped my dress!
我想回家
I want to go home.
今天到此为止
That's enough for today.
当然，我们会重新安排的
Of course, we'll reschedule.
埃丝特，你还好吗?
Esther, you alright?
呃  是的
Uh, yes.
嘿
Hey!
莫蒂西娅
Morticia.
帮我把加纳叫来，好吗?
Get Gunnar for me, would you?
你叫我什么？
What did you call me?
迈克  是她  那个妹妹
Mike, that's her. The sister?
哦  该死，是我的错
Oh, shit, it's my bad.
呃...  叫加纳来
Umm...Get Gunnar.
帕贾斯塔？
Pajalsta?
不如我把你的蛋蛋切下来，喂你吃怎么样
How about I cut your balls off, and feed them to you,
你这该死的混蛋
you fucking shitstain?
是西班牙语吗？ 还是别的？
Was that Spanish, or something?
我不   嘿
I don't.. Hey.
我们走
Let's go.
你妹妹真他妈让人受不了，伙计
Your sister's a fucking trip, man.
说真的，老兄，我爸爸就在那儿
Seriously, dude, my dad's right there.
我不在乎
I don't care.
迈克，搞什么… 我就是我
Mike, what the fuck.. I am what I am.
嘿  亲爱的，你还好吗?
Hey, honey, you okay?
嗯  我的衣服破了
Hm. My dress is ruined.
我们会给你买一件新的
We'll buy you a new one.
我在想， 呃 只是在想
I was thinking, uh, just thinking
我们可以去工作室看看
we can go to the studio.
我很乐意
I would love to.
我不知道这有什么好玩的
If I didn't know any better,
我想你以前从未来过这里
I'd think you've never been in here before.
太美了
So beautiful.
这灯是干什么用的?
What's the light for?
你不记得了吗?
So you don't remember?
这就是你爸爸出名的地方
This is what your papa is famous for.
这儿
Here.
按这个
Press on this.
是啊，我总是想把那么多东西放进一张画布里
Yeah, I always try to fit so much in to one canvas,
你知道吗  所以我用了隐藏式画法
you know, So I resorted to a hidden layer.
任何事物不能只看表面，对吧?
Nothing is ever just one thing, right?
真酷
So cool.
你有段时间没来了
You haven't been in here in a while.
是，我没有
No, I haven't.
这个是什么?
What's this one?
哦  不
Oh, no.
这个是，呃  我应该把它处理掉的
It's, uh, I should have gotten rid of this.
是谁，那是谁?
Who-who is, who is that?
沉溺于过去是没有用的
There's no use dwelling on the past.
你回家了，这才是最重要的，好吗?
You're home now, that's all that matters, alright?
所以我在想我们可以在画布上涂涂抹抹
So I was thinking we could dust off some canvasses you
看看会有什么结果
know, and see what comes of it.
我很乐意
I'd love to.
你擅长什么
Uh, what's your poison?
油画还是水彩画?
Oils, watercolors?
颜料我都有
I've got it all.
- 木炭画          - 木炭画
- Charcoal.   - Charcoal.
好的，选一个物体，然后坐下来
Okay, pick an object and we'll sit down
我们一起画它
and we'll draw it together.
我想画你
I want to draw you.
你想画我吗?
You want to draw me?
耶  好吧
Yeah, okay.
这可是头一回
Well, this is a first.
你想让我摆什么造型?
How do you want me?
我可以，我可以当思考者
I can, I can do the thinker.
当你看那张照片的时候 的样子
The way you were when you were looking at that.
我再也不想回首往事了
That's not a place I want to live anymore.
好了 那就这样吧
There, just like that.
你在那边的时候学会了画画吗?
You learned to paint while you were over there?
你是直接画画，还是…
Would you just draw, or was it, was it also..
不是你想的那样
It wasn't what you think.
还是发生了
It's still happening
尽管发生了这么多事
despite everything that's going on.
艾伦
Allen?
不，他不会在那里
No, he won't be there.
你知道他是如何看待这些事情的
You know how he feels about these things.
那我们明天晚会上见，好吗?
So I'll see you at the gala tomorrow then, okay?
这是有原因的
It's for good cause.
贝丝，带上你的支票簿和吉姆
Beth, just bring your checkbook and Jim.
看在上帝的份上，这是治疗小儿癌症的
It's for pediatric cancer, for Christ's sake.
好了，好多了，谢谢
Okay, that's better, thank you.
我完成了
I'm finished.
真的吗
Already?
你喜欢吗？
Do you like it?
我很喜欢
I love it.
真-真是难以置信
It's-it's incredible.
好的，等我30秒，好吗?
Okay, thirty seconds, alright?
然后我们来看看你还会画什么
And then we're gonna see what you can do with paint.
这是个人隐私
That's private.
哦  我很抱歉
Oh, I'm sorry.
我-我看到你把它带回来了
I-I saw that you brought it back with you,
我觉得它很特别
I thought it was special.
你没敲门?
You don't knock?
我在找我的金表
I was looking for my gold watch.
没关系，我肯定会找到的
It's OK, I'm sure it will turn up.
对不起
Sorry!
埃丝特的财产
Property of Esther.
妈咪带我去看邪恶女巫
Mummy took me to Wicked.
妈咪
Mummy.
你好 妈咪
Hello, mummy.
谢谢你 妈咪
Thank you, mummy.
我懂  妈咪
I know, mummy.
妈咪
Mummy.
哈  妈咪
Huh! Mummy.
你们不会相信埃丝特有多厉害
You're not gonna believe what Esther can do.
我们在工作室待了一个下午
We spent the afternoon in the studio.
她给我画了一幅肖像
She drew a portrait of me.
她比我20多岁时更有才华
She's got more talent than I had when I was in my 20s.
那怎么可能?
How's that possible?
四年前她还在画简笔画
Four years ago she was drawing stick figures.
冷静
Easy.
什么
What?
想想四年前你在哪里
Think about where you were four years ago.
现在你是击剑冠军了
Now you're a fencing champion.
是啊，真是太不可思议了
Yeah, just, it's impressive.
也许你可以给我画一幅肖像
Maybe you can make a portrait of me.
这很好吃，妈咪
This is delicious, mummy.
谢谢你
Thank you.
有什么问题吗?
Is something wrong?
不不
No, no.
我 我只是
I'm-I'm just..
你在等人吗?
Were you expecting someone?
我只是想进来跟埃丝特打个招呼
Just thought I'd pop in to say hi to Esther.
看看谁来拜访了
Look who came for a visit.
哦，很抱歉打扰你们吃饭
Oh, I'm sorry to interrupt dinner.
这是 呃  你失踪时帮助过我们的警官
This is, uh, the police officer who helped us when you went missing.
他是一个朋友
He's a friend.
我只是来欢迎你回家，埃丝特
I just came to say welcome home Esther.
谢谢
Thank you.
对不起，我失陪一下
Excuse me for a moment.
你应该知道，我们的儿童心理学家觉得
You should know, um, our child psychologist feels
埃丝特应该说出她的故事
Esther should tell her story within the confines of a...
而不是和我这样的警察在一起
And not with a cop like me.
别担心  我明白
Don't worry, I get it.
但埃丝特确实从我们的小镇上失踪了
But Esther did vanish from our little town,
这仍然是一个令人关切的问题
and that remains a concern.
我需要知道是否还有危险
I need to know if there's still a danger.
我今早跟西格医生谈过了
I spoke to Dr. Segar this morning.
这样合适吗?
Is that appropriate?
她告诉我她愿意参加小组讨论
She told me she's open to a group discussion
就在明天早上
tomorrow morning.
只是想看看是否一切都好
Just to see if everything's alright.
妈咪，你的晚会就在明天
Mummy, your gala is tomorrow.
那我们改天再做吧
We'll do it the following day then.
这很重要
It's important.
我是说，当然
I mean, sure.
如果真的那么重要，我们会去的
If it's that important, we'll be there.
你的杯子还是空的
You forgot to fill your glass.
嗯 欢迎回家，埃丝特
Well, um, welcome home, Esther.
这话你已经说过了
You said that already.
埃丝特
Now, Esther.
哦  没事，她说得对
Oh, it's okay, she's right.
我送你出去
I'll walk you out.
我很抱歉你住在这里
I'm sorry you live here.
你知道吗  我想我会继续待在这里
You know.. I think I'll stay here
一段时间的
for a while.
我觉得西格医生有点不对劲
I think something's going on with Dr. Segar.
上次见面时她似乎在暗示
She seemed to be implying in our last meeting
埃丝特在撒谎
that Esther is lying.
这简直是疯了
That's insane.
也许她需要去看心理医生
Maybe she needs to see a therapist.
我知道，对吧？
I know, right?
这  这是什么？
What...what is this?
你的约会
Your date.
你要来吗?
You're coming?
是的  当然，我必须来
Yeah, of course, I'm coming.
你是我的妻子
You're my wife.
我可以帮你对付几个有钱的混蛋
I can deal with a few rich pricks for you.
埃丝特怎么办
What about Esther?
嗯  加纳在呢
Well, Gunnar's here.
她会没事的   好吧
She'll be fine. Right?
什么?你想让我待在家里吗?
What? Do you want me to stay home?
不不
No. No.
你知道的   自从埃丝特回来了以后
You know, it seems like since we got Esther back,
我们也找回了自己
we got us back too.
我完全同意
I couldn't agree more.
你穿衣服需要多长时间?
How long do you need to get dressed?
我可以很快
I can be quick.
是吗
Yeah?
我也可以很快
I can be quick too.
对不起
I'm sorry.
不  很可爱
No, they're cute.
把门关上
Just close the door.
什么
What?
不
No.
不  不  不  不  不  不  不  不
No, no, no, no, no, no, no, no.
哦  我的天
Oh, my God.
你知道我花了多少钱买这条裙子吗?
Do you know how much I spent on this dress.
让我看看
Let me look.
哦 伙计
Oh, man.
我可以用安全别针搞定
I can fix that, with a safety pin.
对，或者订书钉
Right, or staples.
订书钉会有用的
Staples will work.
当我们不在的时候 你有责任照顾你妹妹
You're responsible for looking after your sister while we're gone.
我们相信你，好吗
We're trusting you, okay.
是  爸爸    我明白
Yeah, dad. I got it.
你看起来棒极了
You look incredible.
我们要走了
We're off.
可能要过了半夜才回家，好吗
Probably won't be home till after midnight, okay.
所以，不要让她熬夜太晚
So, don't let her stay up too late.
你有钥匙吗?
You have the keys?
知道了
Copy that.
你看起来真美
You look nice.
谢谢
Thanks.
晚安，亲爱的
Have a good night, honey.
晚安
Night.
那我们现在要做什么呢?
So what are we going to do?
我们
We?
Whoo!
♪ We got a lot of time And it sure feels right ♪
♪ 'Cause you reached In your pocket ♪
♪ You've got to win a little ♪
♪ Lose a little ♪
♪ And always have The blues a little ♪
哦，出来了 该死，伙计们，我很抱歉
Oh, it's out. Oh, shit, guys, I'm sorry.
我憋了太久了
I was holding on to it for too long.
好吧，加纳，你妹妹和你记忆中的
Okay, is it, Gunnar, is your sister different
不一样了吗?
than you remember?
我的意思是. .你觉得呢?
I mean.. What do you think?
她在某个东欧性集中营待过
She's been at some eastern European sex gulag.
迈克
Mike!
是的
Yeah, no.
她，呃  她不一样，好吧
She, uh, she's different, alright.
她现在有口音了
She's got an accent now.
她穿的像莉兹·玻顿
And she dresses like Lizzie Borden.
太他妈奇怪了
It's so fucking weird.
莉兹·玻顿是谁
Who is Lizzie Borden?
♪ Sha la-la la... ♪
呃 一个用斧头杀了父母的疯女人
Uh, some crazy chick who killed her parents with an axe.
呃 嘿 埃丝特
Uh, hey, Esther.
你为什么不去看个电影什么的?
Why don't you go watch a movie or something?
不
No.
埃丝特，这不是你的地盘
Esther, this isn't your scene.
去看你的电影
Go watch a movie.
玩蛋去吧你
Go fuck yourself.
嘿  加纳，你知道我喜欢什么
Hey, Gunnar, you know what I like.
走
Go.
无论如何,  干杯
Anyway, cheers.
耶，我要喝他妈的
Yeah, I'll fucking drink to that.
我们刚才在说什么?
What were we talking about?
晚上好
Evening.
嘿，我父母不在这里
Hey, my parents aren't here.
他们在妈妈的晚会上
They're at mom's gala.
真倒霉
Just my luck.
在开派对吗？
Having a party?
不，只是几个朋友
No, it's just a few friends.
大街上都能闻到大麻的味道
You can smell the weed from the street.
什么
What?
呃 我不知道，我不知道你在说什么
Uh, I don't know, I don't know what you're talking about.
听着，这里什么事都没有，好吗?
Look, nothing's going on here, okay?
不如我告诉我父母你来过
So, um, why don't I just tell my parents that you stopped by
然后我们就把这一切都忘了吧?
and we can just forget all about this?
好吗
Cool?
好的
Cool.
好
Good.
我走之前能去趟洗手间吗?
Mind if I hit the restroom before I go?
是的  嗯   随便吧，当然可以
Yeah. Um, whatever, yeah, sure.
太棒了
That was a blast.
难怪那些小气的百万富翁排着队
No wonder those uptight millionaires line up to give
给基金会捐款
the foundation money.
哦   不  是酒的问题
Oh, no. It's the booze.
不是酒的问题，亲爱的
It's not the booze, hon.
是主人
It's the host.
你能激励出人们最好的一面
You bring the best out of people.
我只希望这房子还在
I just hope the house is still standing.
我是说当我16岁的时候，我差点
I mean when I was 16, I-I nearly,
我差点把房子烧了
I nearly burned the house down.
不，加纳不会这么做的
No, Gunnar would never do that.
谁说我在扯加纳的
Who says I'm talking about Gunnar?
埃丝特  我们回来了
Esther? We're home.
埃丝特
Esther?
萨恩研究所？
The Saarne Institute?
埃丝特
Esther?
如果你不是埃丝特，那好你到底是谁？
If you're not Esther, who the hell are you?
你怎么知道我不是埃丝特？
How did you know that I'm not Esther?
她自己的母亲都不知道
Her own mother doesn't even know.
是的，孩子，她知道
Yeah, kid, she does.
该死的
Damn it.
妈咪
Mummy?
你他妈的在看什么?
What the fuck are you looking at?
所以，让我把事情搞清楚
So, let me get this straight.
你是个成年女人，还是个通缉犯?
You're a grown-ass woman and a wanted criminal?
这真是  太操蛋了
That is...beyond fucked up.
顺便说一句，我现在只能做这个了
This is all I ever do anymore by the way.
替我的孩子们收拾残局
Clean up after my kids.
别担心
Don't worry about it.
妈咪会处理好的
Mommy will take care of it.
妈咪会处理好一切的
Mommy takes care of everything.
当加纳告诉我唐纳警官来过我家时
When Gunnar told me Donnan came to the house,
我就知道会在这里找到你
I knew I'd find you here.
你本可以有机会把我们洗劫一空然后消失，
You could've robbed us blind and disappeared the second you
但你没有
had a chance, but you didn't.
这是为什么呢?
Why is that?
你想得更大
You're thinking bigger.
对吧
Right?
扮演角色，操纵我们，   一年后，我们就会遭遇
Play the part, manipulate us.. And a year from now we meet
悲惨的意外
with some tragic accident.
我的猜测接近了没有？
Am I getting warm?
让我走
Let me go.
你永远不会再看到我了
You'll never see me again.
这正是我所担心的
That's exactly what I'm afraid of.
我们不能让埃丝特失踪两次，对吧?
We can't have Esther disappear twice now, can we?
她并没有消失
She didn't disappear.
已经没有什么 我可以为她做的了
There was nothing that I could do for her.
为时已晚
It was too late.
加纳..他总是对她很粗暴
Gunnar.. He was always way too rough with her.
那天晚上，一切都太过了
That night it just went too far.
我当时还能怎么做呢?
What was I supposed to do?
把我剩下的唯一的孩子交出去吗？  就像扯淡的兄妹之情一样？
Hand over the only child I had left over some sibling bullshit
那不是太过了吗?
that went too far?
我全心全意地爱着我的女儿
I loved my daughter, with all my heart.
但母亲会保护她的家人，无论如何
But a mother protects her family, no matter what.
如果你认为   我会让某个变态侏儒
And if you think, that I'm gonna let some psycho dwarf
毁掉我所建立的一切… 那你就错了
destroy what I have built.. You're mistaken.
这家人乘着该死的五月花号来到这里
This family came over on the fucking Mayflower
建立了这个国家
and built this country.
我们很在乎
We matter.
艾伦很在乎
Allen matters.
当他得到埃丝特还活着的消息时
When he got the news Esther was alive..
他脸上的幸福……
The happiness on his face...
我必须让这一切继续下去
I had to make this work.
艾伦并不知道埃丝特怎么了
Allen doesn't know what happened to Esther.
你要帮我确保他永远不会知道
And you are gonna help me make sure that he never does.
只有一件事比孩子的死更可怕
There's only one thing worse than the death of a child.
那就是孩子的失踪
And that is a child who is missing.
埃丝特的失踪改变了艾伦
Esther's disappearance changed Allen.
改变了他的为人
Changed who he was.
他本该不是这样的人
Who he is supposed to be.
但现在 你  就是答案
But you are the answer.
你和我还有机会扭转局面
You and I have a chance to turn this mess
把这变成一个互惠互利的协议
into a mutually beneficial arrangement.
埃丝特在下面，对吧?
Esther's down there, isn't she?
不准你这么说她的名字
Don't you fucking say her name.
好吧  你骗进了我的家庭
Okay. You conned your way into my family.
你选了这个角色，现在你他妈的就得给我表演好
You chose this role, and now you're gonna fucking play it.
梅斯警佐
写这封信是为了通知你，根据附件的请假表，我将立即开始休假
期间无法通过电邮或手机找到我
有事请联系莱希警官
万事如意
唐纳警探
所以你现在可以当埃丝特了   过着任何人都喜欢的生活
So you can be Esther for now and live a life that anyone
打死都想要的生活
would kill to have.
不然你就得背这个黑锅   然后被遣送回爱沙尼亚
Or you take the fall for this and get shipped back to Estonia
而且还戴着手铐
in handcuffs.
你怎么说?
What do you say?
对不起，吓到你了
I'm sorry I scared you.
对不起
I'm sorry.
我们不该丢下你不管的
We should've never left you alone.
发生了什么事?
What happened?
她从自行车上摔了下来
She fell off her bike.
我在路边发现了她
I found her by the side of the road.
亲爱的，你骑自行车做什么
Honey, what were you doing on a bike.
来吧，让我们进去吧
Come, let's-let's go on.
妈妈，我很抱歉
Mum, I'm so sorry.
住口
Stop.
搞什么鬼!
What the fuck!
所以这是什么意思?
So what does this mean?
哦, 这意味着……她并不是个孩子
Oh, it means.. She's not a kid.
她是个成年女人，我们不能低估她
She is a grown woman and we cannot underestimate her.
不，她不止如此，母亲，她是个神经病
No, she's more than that, mother, she's a psychopath
而且还住在我们家
living in our fucking house.
嘘
Shh.
所以我们就只能和这个人一起生活吗?
So we just have to live with this person?
我没那么说
I didn't say that.
那我们能不能，你知道的    伪装成一场意外?
So then can we just, you know, make it look like an accident?
还为时过早
It's too soon.
我们需要考虑这一点
We need to think about this.
所以她现在控制了我们?
So she just owns us now?
不 不
No, no.
她和我们一样会失去很多东西
She has much to lose as we do.
听着，我们都没想到会这样
Look, neither of us were expecting this.
所以现在，我们得盯着她
So for now, we just keep an eye on her
当时机成熟时，我们会结束这一切
and when the time is right, we'll end it.
太疯狂了
This is insane.
即使对于我们来说
Even for us.
OK
看到了吗，先上弦
See that, it's set in fire.
把它拉紧，就像这样
Pull it back, just like that.
拿着箭，放进去，滑动它
You get the bow, whip it in and slide it.
看这个，你在看吗
See this, are you watching?
是的    你  很好
Yeah, and you.. Nice.
你看到了吗
You see that?
这就是我要说的
That's what I'm talking about.
我们今天要见西格医生
Our meeting with Dr. Segar is today.
如果那天你没跟那只鹦鹉说话的话    我们就不会有这个问题了
A problem we wouldn't have if you hadn't talked to the parrot.
雪梨是一只金刚鹦鹉
Sydney was a macaw.
一只什么
A what?
所有的金刚鹦鹉都是鹦鹉
All macaw's are parrots.
但不是所有该死的鹦鹉都是金刚鹦鹉
But not all fucking parrots are macaws.
那我们该怎么办?
What are we gonna do about that?
哦  我们得取得她的相信
Oh, we make her believe.
一起合作
Together.
我们的目标之一就是帮助埃斯特适应新环境
One of our goals here is helping Esther acclimate back
融入家庭单位的生活
into life within the family unit.
其中一部分是记住你们共同的过去
Part of that is remembering your shared history.
你们共度的时光，你们以前一起做的有趣的事情
Moments you had, the fun things you did together before.
奥尔布赖特先生,  什么样的记忆 对你和埃丝特来说最重要?
Mr. Albright, what's a memory that means a lot to you and to Esther?
哦，天哪，太多了
Oh, God, there are so many.
哈
Huh?
嗯，在巴黎过圣诞节
Um, there was Christmas in Paris.
在托斯卡纳的夏天
The summer in Tuscany.
黄石公园吗?
Yellowstone?
是的, 那是
Yeah, that's up there.
那时我六岁
I was six.
我们看到熊. .还有一只花栗鼠偷了我的三明治
We saw bears.. And a, a chipmunk stole my sandwich.
哦  天啊，有好多花栗鼠
Oh, my God, there were so many chipmunks.
嗯   还有什么，埃丝特?
Mm-hmm, what else, Esther?
具体点
Be specific.
我们住在麋鹿岭农场和骑马
We stayed at Elk Ridge Ranch and rode horses.
我的是一匹小矮马，名叫“金块”，而爹地的马
Mine was a pony named Nugget and daddy's horse
叫“弹力”
was called Stretch.
有一次当“弹力”弯下腰来吃草时
And this one time when Stretch leaned down to eat grass,
爹地就一头栽在地上
daddy fell right over his head onto the ground.
他满脸都是土
He had dirt all over his face.
甚至连牙齿里都是!
It was even in his teeth!
真不敢相信你会讲这个故事
I can't believe you're telling this story.
哦 天啊，它在你牙齿里好几天呢
Oh, my God, it was in your teeth for days.
总之，埃丝特展现了健康的人生观
In summary Esther exhibits a healthy outlook on life.
尤其是重新进入这个家庭单元
Especially re-entering into this family unit.
她身体机能很好
She's highly functioning.
情绪很好
Emotionally well.
就是这些了
That is all.
今天有很多人要来
There are people coming over today.
就是为了能见你
Just to see you.
他们是我们的朋友，也都认识埃斯特，所以
They're friends of ours, who knew Esther, so, enough with
别再怒视我了，好吗?
the glowering, okay?
埃丝特是个淑女
Esther is a lady.
我想我得搞点破坏了
I think I'm gonna have to do some damage.
好了
Okay.
我认为我们做得很好
I think we did good.
大家都认为埃丝特会崩溃
Everyone expects Esther to be broken.
他们真正想要的是一个圆满的结局
What they really want is a happy ending.
我们要假装粉红色是你最喜欢的颜色
We are gonna pretend that pink is your favorite color.
哦, 天鹅绒
Ooh, velvet.
秘诀是
The secret.
给他们讲个他们愿意相信的故事
Let's give them a story they want to believe.
这一件是我最喜欢的
This one is my favorite.
你最喜欢什么颜色？
What's your favorite color?
粉红
Pink.
非常   非常好
Very, very good.
现在，你说你会画画
Now, you say you can paint.
你还会什么
What else can you do?
我非常想念我的家人
I missed my family very much.
很高兴能回来
It's lovely to be back.
现在你的计划是什么 ，年轻的小姐?
And what are your plans now, young lady?
我的计划是什么，妈咪?
What are my plans, mummy?
完全没有
Absolutely nothing.
我不会再让你离开我的视线了
I'm not letting you out of my sight.
让我直说了吧
So let me get this straight.
你30岁了？
You're 30?
请马上离开我的房间
Get out of my room, now, please.
这不是你的房间
It's not your room.
这是我死去的妹妹的房间
It's my dead sister's room.
你不是她，永远都不是
You're not her and you never will be.
明白了吗?
Is that perfectly clear?
滚蛋
Fuck off.
说话注意点，怪胎
Watch your mouth, freak.
你知道吗, 我很高兴一切都公开了
You know, I'm glad everything's out in the open now.
因为我受够了假装跟你演戏
'Cause I'm done pretending like you belong here.
你没有
You don't.
这是我的房子，我的家人
This is my house, my family.
它永远不会是你的
And it will never be yours.
只要你在这个屋檐下
As long as you're under this roof,
你和我都知道这一点
you and I will have an understanding.
事实是这样的
Here's what it is.
你他妈的属于我
I fucking own you.
再这样，我就像杀埃丝特一样杀了你
Do that again and I'll kill you like I killed Esther.
只要我打个电话，你就会被关进劳改营
One call from me, and you're right back in that gulag.
你也会下去的
You'd go down too.
为什么，就因为那个非法移民逃亡的精神病人说的话吗?
Why, because of what the illegal immigrant fugitive mental patient said?
祝你好运
Good luck with that.
这里是美国
This is America.
像我这样的人很重要
People like me matter.
如果你不是埃丝特，那就意味着
And if you're not Esther, ah, it just means
埃丝特又失踪了
Esther's missing again.
妈妈对此有意见
Mom has a problem with that.
但我没有
I don't.
回头见，怪胎
See you later, freak.
你今晚要睡得像个该死的婴儿
You are gonna sleep like a fucking baby tonight.
我用迷迭香和橄榄酱做了烤羊肉
I made roast lamb with rosemary and tapenade.
我知道，埃丝特不喜欢这样
And I know, Esther doesn't like it.
所以我做了你最喜欢的
So I made your favorite.
哦，就像以前一样
Oh, just like the old days.
明天就要进城了，我真的很兴奋
I'm really excited about going into the city tomorrow.
我要向画廊展示我的作品
I'm gonna show the gallery what I've been working on.
这听起来太棒了
That sounds wonderful.
这都要感谢你
Well, it's all thanks to you.
做自己喜欢的事情   让我重新找到了快乐
I rediscovered the joy I once felt doing what I loved.
我觉得自己又像个孩子了
I feel like a kid again.
你想来吗？
Do you wanna come?
我很乐意!
I would love to!
埃丝特和我已经有约了
Oh, Esther and I already have plans.
哦
Oh.
什么计划
What plans?
是一个惊喜
It's a surprise.
好的
Okay.
那就改天吧
Well, another time then.
你又开始画画了，真是太好了，爸爸
It's great that you're painting again, dad.
嗯，是的
Well, yeah.
我可以失陪一下吗?
May I be excused?
哦，别忘了你的…  你可以在楼上吃，没关系
Oh, don't forget your.. You can eat upstairs, it's okay.
亲爱的，怎么了?
Honey, hey, what's wrong?
爸爸, 她很好
Dad, she's fine.
给她点空间
Just give her some space.
她很好
She's fine.
是的
Yeah.
她可能钢琴弹得太累了
She's probably tired from all that piano playing.
我可以进来吗?
Can I come in?
你还好吗?
Are you okay?
刚才下面发生了什么?
What happened down there?
我  呃 我不太喜欢妈咪做的菜
I, uh, I don't really like mummy's cooking.
你能保守秘密吗?
Can you keep a secret.
我也不喜欢
I'm not crazy about it either.
听着，晚上是我最喜欢画画的时间
Oh, listen, um, night time's my favorite time to paint.
你想和我一起去吗?
Do you, you wanna come join me?
是的，我很乐意
Yes, I would love to.
待会楼下见
I'll see you downstairs.
这地方太棒了
This is a such a great space.
我很高兴你喜欢它
I'm glad you like it.
每个艺术家都需要一个空间来释放他们内心的古怪
Every artist needs a space to let their inner weirdo out.
我们可以看到美, 激情
We get to see beauty, passion,
看到别人都不知道的地方
where others don't even know to look.
我真喜欢这个
I really like that.
这么多的颜料
So much paint.
是的，我是个邋遢的画家
Yeah, I'm a messy painter.
会让你妈妈发疯的
Drives your mother crazy.
我想 我今晚就到此为止吧
I think I'm, I think I'm done for the night.
记得把灯关掉
Just turn the lights off.
祝你晚安
Have a good night.
看来你们俩玩得很开心
Looks like you two had fun.
他是对的
He's right.
你很有天赋
You are talented.
他很了不起，不是吗?
He is something, isn't he?
你就这么痴心妄想吗
Are you so utterly delusional to think that
以为他会要你吗?
he would want you?
"惊喜，我不是你女儿，我是个变种骗子 ”
"Surprise, I'm not your daughter, I'm a mutant grifter."
他会像大多数男人一样厌恶你的
He would be as repulsed by you as I suspect most men are.
如果你不介意的话，我要上楼去
Well, if you'll excuse me, I'm gonna go upstairs
跟我老公上床了
and fuck my husband.
你回来后，他真的变了一个人
He really is a new man since you came back.
真是多谢你了
Thanks for that.
嘿 你
Hey, you.
我觉得埃丝特会很不开心的   因为我们去画廊
I think Esther's really bummed about not coming to the
没带上她
gallery with me.
听着，我很高兴你和埃丝特有共同的绘画爱好
Listen, I love that you and Esther have painting in common.
我只是，我和她没有那种感觉
I just, I don't have anything like that with her.
我希望今天能陪着她
I was hoping that I could spend the day with her
也许我们可以找点东西分享
and maybe we could find something to share.
而且集中精力对你也有好处，对吧?
Plus it would be good for you to be focused, right?
我是说，如果萨尔斯喜欢你的作品，也许你就能办一个画展
I mean if Sals likes what he sees then, maybe you get a show
重新回到舞台上
and you get back out there.
是, 那好吧
Yeah, okay.
我们没事的    对吧
We're not hurting, are we?
不  不
No, no.
完全没有
Not at all.
你是一位伟大的画家
You are a great painter.
人们十分怀念你的作品
People miss seeing your work.
谢谢你
Thank you.
那是培根吗?
Is that bacon?
哦,这是天堂!
Oh, it's heaven!
早上好, 爹地
Good morning, daddy.
我可以...
Can I...
好的，请吧
Yes, please.
还有什么是你不会的吗?
Is there anything you can't do?
妈咪
Mummy?
哦 不   谢谢
Oh, no, thanks.
我要像往常一样做冰沙?
I'm gonna make my usual-- Smoothie?
希腊酸奶，羽衣甘蓝，亚麻籽和柠檬汁
Greek yogurt, kale, flax seeds and lemon juice.
就像你喜欢的那样
Just the way you like it.
试试
Try it.
我  我不是很饿
I'm-I'm not really that hungry.
我  我想要
I'll-I'll have it.
给我
Here.
不，这个是特别的，只为妈咪
No, this is special, just for mummy.
我为你做的
I made it for you.
哦  亲爱的，你真好
Oh, sweetie, that's so nice of you.
但我更喜欢自己做
But I prefer to make my own.
特里西娅, 拜托
Tricia, come on.
试试
Try it.
好
Good.
真好吃
Delicious
谢谢
Thank you.
特里西娅  你没事吧
Tricia, you okay?
我很好.
I'm good.
是吗
Yeah?
我知道你想和我一起去
I know you wanted to come with me.
但我觉得和你妈妈共度一天对你很有好处
But I think it'll be really good for you to spend the day with your mom.
不过我想给你看样东西
I wanted to show you something, though.
给你
Here.
就是里面那个
It's the one in the center.
伍德利学院的院长是我的朋友
Dean at Woodley is a friend of mine.
伍德利是全国最好的艺术学校
Woodley is the best art school in the country.
你太棒了，埃丝特
You're scary good, Esther.
我可以给他们看吗?
Can I show it to them?
我很喜欢
I would love it.
谢谢你
Thank you.
你能把这个拿到站台上去吗
Can you bring this up to the platform.
我去买点咖啡
I'm just gonna get some coffee.
给爸爸妈妈的
Just for mom and dad.
好了 待会在上面见
Okay. I'll see you up there.
小心看路  孩子
Watch where you're going, kid!
她是你的吗?
Does she belong to you?
是的 是我的
Yes, she does.
发生了什么事?
What happened?
哦  没什么  没事
Oh, nothing. It's fine.
埃丝特绊倒了
Esther tripped.
抱歉，久等了
Sorry, it took forever.
不 不
No, no.
让他们大吃一惊，好吗?
Knock 'em dead, okay?
爹地，带我一起去
Daddy, take me with you.
哦，亲爱的，我也想
Oh, honey, I wish.
下次吧
Next time.
好吗
Alright?
好吧，你要赶不上火车了
Alright, you're gonna miss your train.
回头见  亲爱的   再见
See you later, honey. Ciao.
放松点，妈妈
Easy, mom.
你认为你他妈的能杀了我吗?
You think you can fucking kill me?
拿着
Take this.
味道就像该死的垃圾
Tastes like fucking garbage.
我们的约定结束了
Our arrangement is over.
你他妈的死定了
You're fucking dead.
嘿
Hey!
啊
Argh!
妈妈
Mom!
哦 我操
Oh, fuck!
贱人
Bitch!
打开那该死的门
Open the goddamn door.
埃丝特
Esther!
亲爱的, 来吧
Sweetie, come on.
你不
Don't you--
♪ Just a steel town girl On a Saturday night ♪
♪ Lookin' for The fight of her life ♪
♪ In the real-time world No one sees her at all ♪
♪ They all say she's crazy ♪
♪ It can cut you like a knife ♪
♪ If the gift becomes the fire ♪
♪ On a wire between Will and what will be ♪
♪ She's a maniac Maniac on the floor ♪
♪ And she's dancing Like she's never danced before ♪
♪ And she's dancing like... ♪
我很抱歉  我是不是开得太快了?
I'm sorry. Was I driving too fast?
你一定是埃丝特
You must be Esther.
我要去医院
I need to go to the hospital.
你没事
You're fine.
感觉就像被捅了他妈的一千刀
It feels like I'm being stabbed a thousand fucking times.
莱希警官！
Officer Leahy!
哦，我的上帝！
Oh, my God!
你能安静两秒钟吗
Can you just be quiet for like two seconds.
什么
What?
我们已经找到了，埃丝特
We've located, Esther.
真的？
You did!
我正要带她回家
I'm bringing her home.
哦
Oh.
对了，我也通知了艾伦
Oh, and I've informed Allen as well.
好的 再见
Okay, bye.
该死
Fuck!
你没事的
You're okay.
非常感谢
Thank you so much.
哦, 我的天啊
Oh, my goodness.
哦
Oh.
非常感谢
Thank you so much.
埃丝特回来后行为一直很不稳定
Esther's behavior has been so erratic since she got back.
说实话，这真的很难
To be honest, it's been really hard.
我的意思是，经常撒谎
I mean there's constant lying
经常爆发愤怒，还有……
and these outbursts of anger and...
有时 她甚至开玩笑 说自己受伤了
Sometimes she even jokes about hurting herself
我觉得她不是在开玩笑
and I don't think she's really joking.
你让她去看心理医生了吗?
You have her in therapy?
是的 是的
Yes, yes.
看看谁回来了
Look who's back.
起来
Get up.
我们现在就动手  马上
We're doing this...now.
嗯 是到该死的时候了
Well, it's about goddamn time.
我操
Fuck.
我受够你了
I am done with you.
已经没什么值得你留在这里了
Nothing is worth having you in this house.
你的自杀会伤透爸爸的心的
Your suicide is gonna break daddy's heart.
但他会撑过去的
But he'll get over it.
去死吧 你这怪胎
Just die, you freak!
她在哪
Where is she?
我,呃,我,呃,   我不是故意的
I, uh, I, uh, I didn't mean to.
哦，这真是太棒了
Oh, that's just brilliant.
就这么发生了
It just happened.
特里西娅
Tricia.
嗨  亲爱的
Hi, honey.
警察刚打电话给我
The police just called me.
哦 我知道
Oh, I know.
我 我很抱歉
I'm, I'm sorry.
都是我的错
It was my fault.
埃丝特在店里走丢了，我，我慌了
Esther wandered off at the store and I-I just, I panicked.
但我打电话给莱希警官，他们找到了她
But I called Officer Leahy and, and they found her.
- 哦 好        - 妈妈
- Oh, good. - Mom.
什么
What?
嗯，我在火车上…
Well, I'm-I'm on the train..
稍等
Hold on.
好吧，我  我在火车上… 我会……
I'm-I'm coming back home. I'll be...
下楼去解决它
Go downstairs and finish it.
什么
What?
下楼去解决它
Go downstairs and finish it.
特里西娅,你还在吗?
Tricia, are you still there?
特里西娅, 一切都还好吗
Tricia, is everything okay?
特里西娅   我  我现在就回家
Tricia, I-I'm coming home now.
什么
What?
我要回家了
I'm coming home.
呃 那你和萨尔的会面呢?
Uh, what about your meeting with Sal?
忘了它吧
Forget about that.
不，亲爱的，我发誓一切都很好
No, sweetie, I swear everything is fine.
埃丝特在这里
Esther is here.
一切都很好
All is well.
但我现在快到车站了
But I'm almost at the station now.
好吧
Okay.
那  你能打车回家吗?
Well, can you please take a cab home?
因为我现在真的很忙
Because I really have my hands full here.
好的
Yeah.
不
No.
该死
Fuck it.
你在这啊
There you are.
埃丝特
Esther.
出来吧，埃丝特
Come on out, Esther.
不管你他妈的叫什么名字
Or whatever the fuck your name is.
你知道的. .  事情不应该是这样子的
You know.. It doesn't have to be like this.
真的吗？加纳
Really, Gunnar?
我相信我们能想出办法的
I'm sure we could figure something out.
你真的相信吗?
You really believe that?
老实说  没有
Honestly, no.
我也不信
Me neither.
该死
Shit.
加纳
Gunnar?
不
No.
你 你做了什么?
What, what have you done?
你做了什么?
What have you done?
你夺走了一切
You've taken everything.
艾伦永远不会是你的
Allen will never be yours.
但我可以向你保证，他会知道你是谁
But I can promise you this, he'll know who you are.
那个操纵我们悲伤的畸形怪胎
The deformed freak who manipulated our grief,
杀了我儿子，还想杀了我
murdered my son and tried to kill me.
直到我做了该做的事
Until I did what had to be done.
打电话给消防队
Call the fire department.
加纳
Gunnar!
坚持住，我来了
Hold on, I'm coming.
爹地，妈米想伤害我!
Daddy, mommy tried to hurt me!
艾伦
Allen!
求求你 救命
Please help!
艾伦
Allen!
别放手
Don't let go.
我坚持不了多久了
I can't hold on much longer.
我抓不住了
I'm losing my grip.
- 爹 爹地  救命       - 坚持住
- Da-daddy, help!  - Hang on.
我来了
I'm coming.
她不是埃丝特!
She's not Esther!
她是个成年女人
She's a grown woman!
- 她骗人         - 什么
- She's lying!  - What?
- 她骗了我们!       - 妈米在撒谎!
- She tricked us! - Mommy is lying!
- 把手给我                - 不，爹地，请救救我
- Give me your hand. - No, daddy, please help me.
特里西娅
Tricia!
搞什么鬼?
What the fuck?
我这么做是为了你们
I did this for you.
为了我们
For us.
这样我们才能在一起
So we could be together.
艾伦，我爱你
Allen, I love you.
你他妈是谁?
Who the fuck are you?
你是一个怪物
You're a monster!
艾伦
Allen!
♪ You've gotta give a little ♪
♪ Take a little ♪
♪ And let your poor heart Break a little ♪
♪ That's the story of That's the glory of love ♪
♪ You've gotta laugh a little ♪
♪ Cry a little ♪
♪ Before the clouds Roll by a little ♪
♪ That's the story of That's the glory of love ♪
♪ As long as there's The two of you ♪
♪ You've got the world And all its charms ♪
♪ And when the world is Through with you ♪
♪ You've got each other's arms ♪
♪ You've gotta win a little ♪
♪ Lose a little ♪
♪ And always have The blues a little ♪
♪ That's the story of That's the glory of love ♪
那场大火夺走了埃丝特的一切
The fire took everything from Esther.
她的家，她的家人
Her home, her family.
整个情况是如此悲惨
The whole situation is so tragic.
真是太可怕了
It's horrifying.
我知道
I know.
好像埃丝特经历的还不够多似的
As if Esther hasn't been through enough already.
被绑架，现在成了孤儿
Abducted, and now an orphan.
没有家庭收留她吗?
With no family to take her in?
以后会发生什么?
What will happen now?
我联系了一家有信誉的收养机构
I've reached out to a reputable adoption agency.
我相信我们会找到一个家庭 让埃斯特得到
I'm confident we'll find a home where Esther can get the
她应得的支持和爱
support and love she deserves.
毕竟，谁不想收养她呢?
After all who wouldn't want to adopt her?
翻译：大旺财